Claudinei Callegari

Brazil, BR

cadicallegari@gmail.com Phone: +55 (48) 9826 4067

Summary

I'm an enthusiastic brazilian software engineer graduated at Universidade Estadual do Oeste do Paraná. Currently I work at Neoway Business Solutions in Florianopolis, south Brazil. Most of my projects now are based on python programming language for scrapy web data and characters recognition. At Neoway I have been developing on Linux environment and using Docker as a tool of deployment. I also had my first contact with Go where I started contributing in small open source projects.

I have dedicated some years of my life working as Full Stack Developer in a startup called DBA. As a result, I participated in all parts of process, from directly contacting customers to understand their requirements, to web development using Ruby on Rails framework, modeling the database, to testing the application. I was also responsible for the frontend development, so hands on JavaScript (AngularJS) and HTML.

After my graduation I worked in different companies with many technologies. I developed in java for Android applications. I was part of a team to develop a protocol of communication in C language for ARM and 8051 processors. I wrote software in Java, Python and a closed tool to convert files used to share informations between companies and banks.

Apart from my technical skills, I'm a committed professional, with can-do attitude, extremely motivated and someone who enjoys to be part of a team.

Education

Universidade Estadual do Oeste do Parana, BSc in Computer Science, December 2011.

Experience

Neoway Business Solutions

May 2016 - Present

Software Developer

Main Technologies: Python, Golang, REST, Docker, Kubernetes;

As a member of datasource team I work mainly with Python language to scrapy data from Internet and Golang for microservices. Recently I got involved with projects that use image processing and deep learning. Most of my projects are deployed using Docker tool and kubernetes to manage my containerized applications.

Inventsys: serial innovation

Fev 2016 - May 2016

 $Free lancer\ And roid\ Developer$

Main Technologies: Java, Android, REST, SQLite;

As a Freelance Java Android developer I helped the company to create an intelligent infrastructure management and urban service solutions. My focus was improving the features related to a device tracker using GPS. I also helped defining the REST API to connect server and devices, the application usability and unit testing.

DBA

May 2013 - May 2016

 $Software\ Engineer\ -\ Full\ Stack$

Main Technologies: Linux, Git, Python, Ruby, JavaScript, Java, Android;

I'm team-member at DBA startup working part of the Parking Meter System project. I'm involved in all parts of the project, this means understand all clients requirements, web development using Ruby on Rails framework, modeling the database and testing the application. I'm also responsible for the frontend development, so hands on JavaScript (AngularJS) and HTML.

I also developed REST APIs to improve the communication with the devices, such as tablets and parking meters. The REST API was developed using Ruby/Grape framework. I've contributed to development of Android applications.

That Android applications were developed using some libs like RxAndroid, Retrofit, SqlBrite, Butterniffe, Dagger, Espresso and Robolectric.

Although I am a software engineer some times it is necessary working as sysadmins doing tasks like Linux and network administration, web servers management (Apache and nginx), log analyse, and so on.

Main tecnologies: Ruby, Rails framework, Android, Postgresql, Grape framework, Linux, Python, DBus, Amazon AWS, Dokku, REST.

Digitro

Sep 2012 - May 2013

Software Engineer

Main Technologies: Linux, Windows, C, SDL;

Implement new features and maintenance of callcenter solution, acting mainly in backup area, using language C with SDL (Specification and Description Language).

Nexxera

Jul 2012 - Sep 2012

Software Engineer

Main Technologies: Linux and Python;

Write scripts using Python, Java and closed tool to convert files "layouts" used to share informations between companies and banks, and vice versa.

Ahgora Jan 2012 - Jul 2012

Jr Software Engineer

Main Technologies: C, Lua, Linux and Java(Android);

Implementation of comunication protocol with language C for ARM and 8051 processors. Development Android application to read RFIDs tags and comunicate to a REST service. Development some applications and modules using language Lua.

ITAI May 2009 - Nov 2011

Trainee

Main Technologies: Linux, C/C++ and Java;

Development with languages C, C++ e Java. Comunication between C and Java using SUN-RPC, JSON. Used Valgrind, Libxml2, Glib

Skills Base

Operating System: Linux (Debian, Ubuntu, CentOS), Windows NT/XP/Vista/7 and OSX;

 ${\it Networkings} \colon {\rm TCP/IP} \ {\rm protocol} \ {\rm suite};$

Progamming Languages: Python, Ruby, C, Golang, Pascal, JavaScript, Java plus some experience with Lua;

Virtualization: Docker, VirtualBox, VMWare, plus some experience with Xen;

Languages: Fluent in Portuguese, Intermediate in English and Spanish;

More Info

• Linkedin: https://br.linkedin.com/in/cadicallegari

• Github: https://github.com/cadicallegari